here's some video footage I caught from
uh the fitness summit last weekend um we
just did like a lunchtime training
session so I I grabbed some footage this
is Jamie Allen I just met her this
weekend um she's 22 years old incredibly
smart she actually won the glute
competition um we had like a glute off
uh with six different women and she was
the winner very firm muscular set of
glutes on her she's a figure competitor
too and just got her Master's degree in
exercise science um here's my girlfriend
Diana she busts out 225 for 15 here this
is actually a PR for her she just
started doing heavy hip thrusts about 6
weeks ago um very strong at the bottom
cuz she's been squatting and deadlifting
but um her top range needed help
actually it's funny because her glutes
are getting bigger from hip
thrust uh compared to how much um
progress she's seen with just squats and
over the past 6 months um here's my
friend Jenny Sinkler uh she didn't know
I was filming this she was actually mad
at me because she's done 135 for 19 but
she wasn't going heavy today she's just
doing sets of five but Jenny is very
strong great form looks beautiful she's
done this for 19 got it for five here's
Jamie
again uh Jamie uh the most she'd ever
done before this this is crazy the most
she's ever hip thrusted was one
165 um for probably like 12 reps and
here she's getting 225 for 10 I'd like
her to go slightly higher up top but
just goes to show you that you can go a
lot heavier with uh you know when you
when you're with someone who knows what
they're doing here's Joy Victoria with
her crazy hot pants on uh Joy just
finished doing like six sets of heavy
squats before this uh and she ends up
getting 14 here um so she's already a
little bit fried from the squats and now
busting out 14 check out the glute
action up top and the posterior pelvic
tilt it's a very good form with joy I
took way too long to take that bar off
okay here's Diana this is a PR for her
she got 275 for 10 and the best part
about this is that she locks it out up
top we've been struggling with this when
she first started she couldn't lock the
weight out up top she had strong glutes
strong hips down low from squatting and
deadlifting but she couldn't lock it out
so now um she's only been doing heavy
hip for like four to 6 weeks and she's
already using 275 and now here's Jamie
again I'd like her to go just a couple
inches higher but this is crazy cuz her
previous best was 165 now she's using 90
lbs heavier going
275 just from learning how to use proper
form she couldn't roll the bar up under
her hip she didn't know how to do that
so I taught her how to do that that
combined with some friendly competition
let her use 90 more pounds okay and then
here's Joy Victoria with six reps again
excellent form um now I I snapped off a
pick of Jamie here the the the first
annual glute glute off Queen here she's
doing pistol squats I really like the
idea of using uh that you know that pole
for balance purposes to help her squeeze
out more reps she did like three sets of
10 here on each legs but this is a
really good glute
exercise um very strong uh again Jim's a
fitness comp figure competitor or I
think she did bikini okay Joy Victoria
so Joy did about six sets of squats with
awesome form she went really heavy then
she did hip thrust now she's doing speed
Deads um I like the double overhand grip
with joy here that strong strong forearm
muscles here but joy has a very awesome
form with everything you look at this
hip action up top she's got to readjust
here so nothing falls out um It's kind
kind of funny wearing those pants you
can kind of Envision the muscles
shortening and and lengthening um but
see here how she squeezes those glutes
really hard to lock on pushes those hips
forward with her glutes this is
excellent
form okay and here's Jen Sinkler again I
don't think she knew I was filming this
but she gets uh 175 for 11 here no big
deal piece of cake Jen is very very
strong uh wearing her her nice purple
outfit
[Applause]
here uh perfect form she's like a
piston busts out 11 reps with 175 and
then her boyfriend Dave with the crazy
beard here then would go up in one arm
deadlift whatever Jen would two arm
deadlift I guess Dave's used over 200 lb
with this so this is nothing to him uh I
had work I had done rack pulls before
this and I'd work my way up to 565 and
Dave just walks up with no warmup and
rack pulls 565 so Dave is very strong uh
Dave got second in the glute competition
next to Roger law he's got freakishly
strong and muscular glutes okay there's
joy again uh busting out explosive
deadlifts very good form him this is
kind of funny here's Jen she gets 235
for four but she didn't chalk up so her
grip starts slipping she was surprised
she didn't know I was filming her but
you'll see next set she gets a lot more
reps after she chalks up here's Diana
205lb squats she's tied out from the hip
thrust so she's skimping on the range of
motion her hips shoot up a little fast
here but she hasn't been squatting real
uh heavy over the last um like six weeks
after a powerlifting competition so
surprised she could get that much weight
but I'd like her going
deeper uh and not having the hips shoot
up so fast here's Jenny uh as you can
see she got two she got four reps last
last set and then chocks up and ends up
getting eight reps very easily so Jen is
very very strong here once I emailed Jen
asking her if she could swing uh the
Beast the 106 lb Cabell she sends me a
video clip back of her busting out like
15 reps like it was nothing Jen's very
strong here's me hip thrusting 405
for2 a lot of people are surprised that
I don't need a bar Pad but I'm lucky my
hip Anatomy is such that my abdominal
muscles and hip flexor muscles stick out
past my bone structure so the bar is
just resting on
muscle uh here's Roger lot Roger won the
glute competition there he is doing some
thrusting
action Roger uh here he is doing chins
with 90 lbs I have watched Roger's
physique improved dramatically over the
last two years from improved diet and um
focusing on he's been lifting higher
reps but Roger won the glute competition
this year he's got alien glutes on him
uh here's Jamie uh Jamie um she actually
set a PR with her deadlifts she thinks
the hip thrust helped her get some like
post activation potentiation in the
glutes or something but you'll see a lot
of I train a lot of um uh bikini and
figure competitors when they deadlift
it's like a stiff leg deadlift cuz they
squat for their quads and then they and
then they deadlift lift for their
hamstrings so her hips are very high you
see there's Roger flexing in the
background and here's here's Jamie doing
205 I think this is a PR but as you can
see she hyperextends her neck a lot I've
never worked with Jamie I'd be trying to
get her have more neutral neck but I'm
not overly concerned with this cuz I've
never met anyone who hurt their neck
deadlifting uh anyway very strong as you
can see and then here's Diana good
falling up with the 205 for four um
hips shoot up a little fast I'd like to
see her use her knees a little more but
Diana used to be very knee dominant now
she's kind of shifted to being hip
dominant but Diana's only been lifting
heavy for like 7 months so very proud of
her she's very
strong uh and then here's me hip
thrusting uh 495 for five I had already
done squats and and rack pulls so I'm a
little bit tired out there's Dave
pushing up on the bench behind me uh so
it doesn't slide out Brian kraw in the
background watching on um I hold the top
for about five seconds and then finally
we've got Roger law doing some twisty
curls on the
TRX uh Roger really likes to pump up his
guns and then just walk around
intimidating people so he's just getting
a good pump on and then he goes around
the fitness summit flexing and and
intimidating folks anyway I hope you
enjoyed the video I hope to see you uh
at next year's fitness summit this is an
awes Awesome event there's nothing like
it um so hope to see you at Fitness
Summit 2014